(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
収録の合間抜け出してゲーセン来ちゃった！
I snuck out during a break in recording and came to the arcade!
え、やばくない？
Wait, isn't this crazy?
え、やばくないこれ？
え、ねねちゃん！
Oh, Nene-chan!
ぺっ！
Pe!
なにこれ？なにこれ？
What is this? What is this?
あ、どうも、こんにちは。
Ah, hello, good afternoon.
あ、こんにちは。
Ah, hello.
あ、ちょっと、え？
Ah, wait, eh?
あ、100円ない！
Ah, I don't have a 100 yen!
100円ない！
I don't have a 100 yen!
すみません、100円。
Excuse me, a 100 yen.
すみません、100円、あの、貸してください。
Excuse me, please lend me a 100 yen.
すみません、あの、もうください。
Excuse me, please, just give it to me.
100円貸してください。
Please lend me a 100 yen.
すみません、あ、すみません。
Excuse me, ah, excuse me.
すみません、あー、もう。
Excuse me, oh geez.
すみません、すみません。
Sorry, sorry.
はっ！はっ！はっ！はっ！はっ！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
始まれ！
Start!
どん！どん！だん！どん！どん！どん！
Don! Don! Dan! Don! Don! Don!
始まれ！始まれ！始まれ！
Start! Start! Start!
え、なに？ねねの何が始まるって言うんだ？
Wait, what? What of Nene's is about to start?
早く始まれ！
Start already!
だんだんだんだんだん！
Dan dan dan dan dan!
なんだなんだ、早く始まれー！
What is it, what is it, start already!
ねねりずむバースデーライブへようこそ！
Welcome to Nenerythm Birthday Live!
まずは遊びたい楽曲を選ぼう！
First, let's choose the song you want to play!
どの曲にしようかなー。
I wonder which song I should pick...
よし、この曲に決定！
Alright, I've decided on this song!
全力女子革命！
Full Power Girl Revolution!
まずはライブ一発目、
First performance of the live,
どの衣装で遊ぼうかなー。
I wonder which outfit I should wear...
これかなー。
Maybe this one...
いやこっち...
No, this one...
いやいやこっち...
No no, this one...
いや、この衣装に決定！
Okay, I've decided on this outfit!
うわー！なにが起こってるんだ！なにが起こってるんだ！
Whoa! What's happening! What's happening!
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
全力女子革命！
Full Power Girl Revolution!
作詞・作曲：Aira (Dream Monster)
Lyrics/Composition: Aira (Dream Monster)
いつもの私で　今日も楽しく
Being my usual self, I'll have fun today too
好きなことをしよう
Let's do what we love
張り切っちゃって　さあ準備だ
I'm all fired up, now I'm ready
おはよう　少し眠たそうな私
Good morning, looking a little sleepy
「かわいい」を今日もまとって
Dressed in "cuteness" again today
全力が一番！
Giving it my all is best!
周りの視線だとか
What others think, or things like that
噂話だとか
Gossip and such
気にしない私は
I don't care about it
私が好きだから
Because I like myself,
いいんだもん
so it's okay!
だからキラキラスマイルで
So with a sparkling smile
オシャレなコーデにチェンジ！
Change into a stylish outfit!
こんなに眩しいのは
The reason I'm so radiant
私だけのヒミツなの
is a secret just for me
キュンってしちゃうかもね
You might just fall in love
可愛いからしょうがない
It can't be helped because I'm cute
自信に溢れてる
Overflowing with confidence
私たちはそうでなくちゃ
is how we should be
明日へのカードめくって
Flip the card to tomorrow
夢の中へ
Into the dream,
バースイン！
birth in!
いつだって自信満々のステージで
Always on a stage full of confidence
今日は私たちがプリンセスなんだから
Because today, we are the princesses
たくさんの出会いと別れがあって
Through many encounters and partings
大切な思い出だから
Because they're precious memories,
大丈夫って思える
I can feel that I'm okay
伝えたくて希望の歌を
I want to convey this song of hope
心は優しさで溢れて
My heart is overflowing with kindness
踊りたくてドレスかざして
Wanting to dance, holding up my dress
素敵な舞台に夢を見る
Dreaming on this wonderful stage
だって1番のアイドル
Because the number one idol
いつか必ずなるんだ
is what I'll definitely become someday
トビラを開けてほら
Open the door and look,
スターは目の前にある
the star is right in front of you
ブザーが鳴り響く
The buzzer resounds,
そんな未来のため
for such a future
マイクに歌声のせて
Putting my voice into the mic,
世界中に笑顔届け
delivering smiles to the whole world
みんな盛り上がってるかーい！
Is everyone having fun!?
1曲目 全力女子革命！
First song, 'Zenryoku Joshikakumei!'
全力でいくぞー！
Let's go at full power!
もっともっと盛り上がれー！
Get even more hyped up!
あーっ！水飲まないとやってらんない！
Ah! I can't keep going without some water!
みんな楽しんでいくぞー！
Let's all have fun!
いっぱいツイートもよろしくねー！
Please tweet a lot as well!
輝く星のように
Like a shining star,
最後はバズリウムチェンジ！
finally, Bazurium Change!
かわいさのヒミツは
The secret of cuteness
私たちだけが知ってるの
is something only we know
今だけ教えるよ
I'll tell you just for now,
ずっとトモダチだから
because we're friends forever
この先どんな景色が待っていてくれるんだろう
I wonder what kind of scenery is waiting for us ahead
キラキラスマイルで
With a sparkling smile
オシャレなコーデにチェンジ！
Change into a stylish outfit!
自信に溢れてる
Overflowing with confidence
私たちはそうでなくちゃ
is how we should be
明日へのカードめくって
Flip the card to tomorrow
夢の中へ
Into the dream,
バースイン！
birth in!
はい！というわけで1曲目お聴きいただきました
Yes! And so, that was the first song you heard,
全力女子革命！でしたー！
'Zenryoku Joshikakumei!'
皆さんこんねねー！ホロライブ5期生、ねぽらぼのー
Hello everyone! I'm Hololive 5th Gen, NePoLaBo's...
みんなの心の、エナジードリンク！
...the energy drink of everyone's heart!
かしゅっ、桃鈴ねねです！
*Psst*, I'm Momosuzu Nene!
さあ今日は、ねねリズムバースデーライブに
Now today, thank you so much for coming
来ていただきまして、誠にありがとうございます！
to the Nene Rhythm Birthday Live!
ねねの枠では、初お披露目になる、
On Nene's channel, this is the first time showing
カラーライズの衣装になります！
the 'Colorize' outfit!
そして今日は、ハッシュタグ
And today, please tweet a lot
『桃鈴ねねお誕生日ライブ2025』で
with the hashtag
たくさんツイートよろしくお願いします！
#MomosuzuNeneBirthdayLive2025!
あとね、MCの時間が8分あるので、全力で水飲みます！
Also, I have 8 minutes for the MC, so I'm drinking water with all my might!
あー、少々お待ちを
Ah, please wait a moment.
はい！というわけで、ジャンジャン行かないとね、
Yes! And so, I've got to keep things moving,
時間なくなっちゃいますので、次の曲行きたいと思いまーす！
or I'll run out of time. So, let's go to the next song!
うーん、どの曲にしようかなー
Hmm, which song should I choose?
うわー、好きなアニメの曲ばっかだ、
Whoa, it's nothing but songs from anime I love.
悩んじゃうよー
I can't decide!
よしっ、次は、この曲に決定！
Alright, it's decided! This is the next song!
『放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい』、
'Housou Code ga Nanbo no Monjai'.
どの衣装で遊ぼうかなー
I wonder which outfit I should use?
銀魂のアニメだからなー、
Since it's from the Gintama anime...
これかな？それかな？
maybe this one? Or that one?
やっぱ和服で決定でしょう！
A Japanese-style outfit is the obvious choice!
T4U、浴衣衣装！
T4U, Yukata outfit!
うわ～、お着替えタイム、お着替えタイム～！
Whoa, changing time, changing time!
ハッ！
Ha!
それでは聞いてください。放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Now then, please listen to: Who Cares About Broadcast Codes!
怖くなんかないもん
I'm not scared at all
だってあなたがいるから
Because you are here
もう覚悟は決めたよ
I've already made up my mind
だから引き返したりしない
So I won't turn back
当たり障りのない
Offense-free
世界 そんなのくそくらえ
World, to hell with that
だって本気の悪ふざけ
Because it's serious mischief
だからまばたきする間
So before you can even blink
及び腰の
Hesitant
エライ人
VIPs
そんなのくそくらえ
To hell with them
だって本気の悪ふざけ
Because it's serious mischief
なれてくると危ない
It gets dangerous when you get used to it
さあ、規制なんか振り払い
Come on, shake off regulations
どこまでもいこう
Let's go anywhere
...見たことのない
...To a world never seen before
新しい世界へ
To a new world
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcast codes!
ブレーキなんて必要ねえ！
I don't need no brakes!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcast codes!
いつも心に
Always in my heart
白装束
White burial shroud
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcast codes!
始末書差し替え関係ねえ！
Replacing disciplinary reports, doesn't matter!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcast codes!
後戻りはできない
There's no going back
なんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares!
怖いものはXXXXX
Scary things are [CENSORED]
だってあの人XXXXXだから
Because that person is [CENSORED]
もうXXXXXは決めたよ
I've already decided on [CENSORED]
だからXXXXXはない
So there is no [CENSORED]
この
This
世界 みんなでXXXXX
World, everyone [CENSORED]
だってXXXXXXXXXXXXX
[CENSORED]
XXXX
XXXXXXXXXXくね！
[CENSORED] right?!
XXXX
[CENSORED]
そんなのXXXXX！
That kind of [CENSORED]!
だってXXXX悪ふざけ
Because [CENSORED] mischief
XXXXXXてきた！
[CENSORED] has come!
さあ、XXXXをXXXX、
Come on, [CENSORED] the [CENSORED],
どこまでもいこう
Let's go anywhere
...見せられない
...Can't show you
XXXX世界へ
To the [CENSORED] world
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcast codes!
XXXX談義で三十分！
Thirty minutes of [CENSORED] talk!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcast codes!
XXXXXを引いてもXXない
Even if I pull [CENSORED], there's no [CENSORED]
XXXXXXがなんぼのXXXXXX！
[CENSORED] is [CENSORED]!
XXXていったらだめなの？
Is it bad to say [CENSORED]?
XXXXXXじゃい！
[CENSORED]!
どうせ放送
Anyway, broadcast
しやしない
They won't
XXXXXXXXX！
[CENSORED]!
(死ぬ時はみんな道連れだよ！)
(When I die, I'm taking you all with me!)
（死ぬ時はみんな道連れネクロマンサー）
(When we die, we're all necromancers going down together!)
はーい！というわけで！
Alright! So!
銀魂の寺門通ちゃんの曲で
That was a song by Terakado Tsuu-chan from Gintama,
『放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい』でしたー！
'Broadcasting Codes? Who Cares!'
あぁ〜！
Aaah!
この曲ね、ピーばっかりで逆にね
There's a theory that this song is actually
歌うのめっちゃ難しい説があったんですけど
super hard to sing because it's full of bleeps,
絶対やりたい曲だったので
but I really wanted to do it,
今日みんなと一緒に遊べて嬉しいです！
so I'm happy I got to have fun with everyone today!
はい、ちょっと水飲みます
Alright, I'm gonna drink some water.
お待たせしました！
Sorry for the wait!
さあ、でもでも！ここからは
Now then! From here on,
コラボパートに行こうと思うので
we're moving into the collaboration part,
ねねの息も整うはず！
so Nene should be able to catch her breath!
というわけで、コラボパート行ってみよう！
So, let's head into the collaboration part!
あー、次はどうする？
Ah, what should we do next?
えー、迷っちゃう！
Eeh, I can't decide!
えー、どうしようかな？
Hmm, what should I pick?
よし、この曲に決定！
Alright, I've decided on this song!
この曲はどの衣装で歌おうかな？
Which outfit should I wear to sing this song?
この衣装？
This outfit?
こっちの衣装もいいな
This one's good too.
この衣装？
This outfit?
うーん、この衣装に決定！
Hmm, I'll go with this one!
うわぁぁぁ！変身！
Waaaah! Transform!
Watch Me
巡りあう糸はきっと
The threads that meet by chance are surely
絡まるようになて
becoming entangled
リアルで感じる熱は
The heat felt in reality
本物の誘惑
is a genuine temptation
ドキドキ高鳴る鼓動と一緒に速度が追いつけない
My heart is pounding, and my speed can't keep up
視線の先に映る君がいて
You are there, reflected in my gaze
目に見えないメロディが
An invisible melody
弾けてる気がしたの
feels like it's bursting
ときめきはいつまでも変わらない夢の証でしょう
This heartbeat is the proof of a dream that will never change
願い事集めてカラフルに彩ってくストーリー
Gathering wishes to color a story vividly
それじゃパッとキメポーズリズムに合わせて
Now then, strike a pose perfectly to the rhythm
Dance Dance 踊ろうよ踏み出して
Dance Dance, let's dance, step out
天使のハートで見せつけていく
Showing off with an angel's heart
これでもうお友達
Now we're already friends
最後はギュッとキメポーズリズムに合わせて
Finally, strike a pose tight to the rhythm
Dance Dance 踊ろうよ駆け抜け
Dance Dance, let's dance, run through
天使の微笑みドキドキさせて
An angel's smile, making hearts flutter
これでもうお友達だね
Now we're already friends, right?
ダラダラしてたらお昼までスースー
If we're lazy, we'll be snoozing until noon
寝不足ヘクトールお腹からグーグー
Sleep-deprived Hector, stomach growling
待っててくれたキミにアンサー最後までアゲてこう
An answer to you who waited, let's keep it up until the end
ノッたりアゲたり案外ノンビリ悪くないねねねね中
Riding, raising, surprisingly leisurely, not bad, in the middle of Nene-Nene
ドキドキ重なる心心中まで追いつけない
Our hearts overlap, can't keep up with the core
いたずらに微笑む君がいて
You are there, smiling mischievously
駆け足で届けたいの
I want to deliver it at a run
魔法みたいにずっと
Forever, like magic
友達はいつまでも忘れない想いを広げて
Friends will never forget, spreading our feelings
どこまでも続いてく同じ未来を見つめたい
I want to gaze at the same future that continues everywhere
きっと夢の中で描いた
Surely, I drew it in my dreams
この瞬間は君だけのために
This moment is just for you
君の心と私の心の距離
The distance between your heart and mine
を繋ぐ糸
is the thread connecting us
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
それじゃパッとあざとくポーズを合わせて
Now then, strike a cute pose together
Dance Dance 踊ろうよ輝いて
Dance Dance, let's dance, shine bright
天使の言葉で虜にしていく
Making you captive with an angel's words
最高の
The best,
キュンとキメポーズ
heart-thumping signature pose!
心に隠してた
The rhythm hidden in my heart,
タンタタタッて踊るよ
I'll dance to it, tan-ta-ta-ta!
ぴょんぴょん跳ねて天使の微笑み
Hopping around with an angel's smile,
ドキドキさせて
making hearts pound.
これでも妄想と同じだね
It's just like my imagination, isn't it?
ぺこら先輩とのデュエット楽しかったー！
That duet with Pekora-senpai was so much fun!
次はどの曲にしようかなー？
Which song should I do next?
まだまだゲストパート、どんどん行くよ！
The guest parts aren't over yet, let's keep going!
次はこのコラボ、いくよ！
Next is this collaboration, let's go!
次はどのお洋服で歌おうかなー？
What outfit should I sing in next?
あのアニメの曲だから...
Since it's a song from that anime...
あの衣装、この衣装、
That outfit, this outfit,
いやいや違うこっちかな？
no, no, maybe this one?
いや、あれ？うーん、違うこっち！
No, wait? Hmm, no, this one!
この衣装に、決定！！
I've decided on this outfit!!
お着替えタ〜イム！
Outfit change time!
よいしょー！
Heave-ho!
パッ！
Ta-da!
一世一代
Once in a lifetime!
鳴っ呼
(Chant)
一切合切
Everything and anything!
自問自答
Soul searching!
以心伝心
Telepathy!
同体
Becoming one!
Only one, Number one
お控えなすってボーイ！
Hold your horses, boy!
順風可憐であれ
Be smooth and lovely,
麗しき校女心
a beautiful schoolgirl's heart.
グッと胸に刻んで
Etch it deeply into your chest.
前髪 スカートの丈
Bangs and skirt length,
校則遵守しましょう
let's follow the school rules.
ビシッと姿勢正して
Straighten your posture firmly.
誠実に受け継ぎたいわ
I want to sincerely inherit
凛々しき教えを
these dignified teachings.
形態 過去 未来 なでしこの
Form, past, and future, the Yamato Nadeshiko's
負けないポリシー
unyielding policy.
一世一代
Once in a lifetime!
Don't be shy 誇らしく 流されたりしないよ
Don't be shy, be proud, don't just go with the flow.
鳴っ呼
(Chant)
ゆっくりと咲かせましょう 清く正しく
Let's bloom slowly, pure and righteous.
Give your best
一番の味方は自分自身
Your best ally is your own self.
みんなもっと もっと
Everyone, more, more!
美しくあれ 真っ直ぐに進みましょう
Be beautiful, let's move straight ahead.
生徒手帳の中の
Following the ideas
思想を地で行くのです
inside the student handbook.
なんて理想的なスタイル
What an ideal style.
学びは温故知新
Learning is discovering new things from the old,
志を磨くべく
to polish our ambitions.
今日も張り切らなくちゃ
I've got to be enthusiastic today too!
有意義にだけど厳しく
Meaningfully, but strictly,
成長過程は
the growth process goes on.
諸行無常をしなくたって 自分のルールで
Even without 'impermanence', use your own rules.
一切合切
Everything and anything!
Don't be cool 覚めないで 心にいつも勇気
Don't be cool, don't wake up, always have courage in your heart.
自問自答
Soul searching!
朗らかに持ち続けて 明日のために
Keep holding it cheerfully for the sake of tomorrow.
Keep your mind
いつだって 自分の味方でいよう
Always be your own ally.
みんなもっと もっと
Everyone, more, more!
しなやかであれ 胸張ってこれからも
Be flexible, with your chest out from now on.
一世一代 鳴っ呼
Once in a lifetime! (Chant)
一切合切 自問自答
Everything and anything! Soul searching!
以心伝心 同体
Telepathy! Becoming one!
Only one, Number one
お控えなすってボーイ！
Hold your horses, boy!
Oh yeah yeah! Don't be shy!
Let's go ガンバレボーイ！
Let's go, do your best, boy!
一切合切 ナンバーワン
Everything and anything, number one!
We are SYD!
Don't be shy 誇らしく
Don't be shy, be proud,
流されたりしないよ
don't just go with the flow.
ゆっくりと咲かせましょう 清く正しく
Let's bloom slowly, pure and righteous.
Give your best
一番の味方は自分自身
Your best ally is your own self.
みんなもっと もっと
Everyone, more, more!
美しくあれ 真っ直ぐに進みましょう
Be beautiful, let's move straight ahead.
みんなお控えなすって!
Everyone, hold your horses!
We are SYD!
お控えなすってボーイ!
Hold your horses, boy!
Let's go ガンバレボーイ!
Let's go, do your best, boy!
一世一代 一切合切 レッツゴー ナンバーワン
Once in a lifetime, everything, let's go number one!
We are SYD!
水着のねねたちどうだった？
How did you like the Nenes in swimsuits?
次はどんな曲でどんな衣装かな？
I wonder what the next song and outfit will be.
ここらへんで落ち着いた曲もいいかもね。
Maybe a calm song would be nice around here.
オッケー！この曲に決定！
Okay! I've decided on this song!
次はどの衣装で歌おうかな？
What outfit should I wear next?
ちょっと落ち着いた感じがいいな。
I want something a bit calm.
この服...あー、ちょっと違うかな？
This outfit... Oh, maybe not?
あの服？
That outfit?
いやいや、もっと落ち着いた感じの色味...
No, no, something with a calmer color...
うーん...
Hmm...
あ！この衣装で決定ー！
Ah! I've decided on this outfit!
ふーむ...
Hmm...
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
今はいいんだよ。
作詞・作曲：MIMI
It's Okay For Now.
Lyrics & Music: MIMI
朝が怖くて起きられない
I'm scared of the morning and can't get up
努力はそんなに向いていない
Effort doesn't really suit me
泣くことだけが得意になる
Only crying becomes something I'm good at
そんな日々の狭間で
In the gaps of those days
ちょっとだけ疲れんだって
I'm just a little tired, I said
星の輝きがしんどくて
The starlight is just too bright
言えないことだけ増えてって
Only the things I can't say keep increasing
俯くように
As if hanging my head
明日が明日が来なければ
If tomorrow, if tomorrow doesn't come
そうしたらきっと楽になれる
Then I'm sure it would be easier
空っぽなのに心が
Even though it's empty, my heart
痛むんだ
it hurts
今日がどうにも寂しくてさ
Today is just so lonely
眠れないままだ夜だけどさ
I still can't sleep, though it's night
いつか幸せって思えるまで
Until the day I can think I'm happy
君は君のままでいてよ
Just keep being yourself
もうさ強がらなくてもいいんだよ
It's okay, you don't have to act tough anymore
過去の夜の涙ひとつ
Every single tear from nights in the past
それを弱く持って歩いていく
I'll walk while holding them gently
それだけで今はいいんだよ
Just that is okay for now
いつか君が笑えるような
So that one day you can smile
歌を歌えるのなら
If I can sing a song like that
僕には何もないけど
I have nothing, but
歌を歌えるのなら
if I can sing a song
泣いちゃう傷の数だけ
For every wound that makes you cry
夜は暖かくなるよ
The night will become warmer
君はさ君のままで笑って
You, just smile while being yourself
今日が
Today...
今日がどうにも寂しくてさ
Today is just so lonely
眠れないままだ夜だけどさ
I still can't sleep, though it's night
いつか幸せって思えるまで
Until the day I can think I'm happy
君は君のままでいてよ
Just keep being yourself
もうさ強がらなくてもいいんだよ
It's okay, you don't have to act tough anymore
過去の夜の涙ひとつ
Every single tear from nights in the past
それを弱く持って歩いていく
I'll walk while holding them gently
それだけで今はいいんだよ
Just that is okay for now
制服のねねたち可愛かったよね！
The Nenes in uniforms were cute, weren't they!
次はどの曲にしよう？
Which song should I choose next?
ゲストは次で最後みたい。
It seems the next guests will be the last.
その前に一回ねねのソロを挟んどく？
Before that, should I squeeze in a Nene solo?
よし！この曲に決定！
Alright! I've decided on this song!
次はアイドル曲だから、アイドルっぽい衣装で歌いたいな。
Since the next one is an idol song, I want to sing in an idol-like outfit.
どの衣装にしようかな？
Which outfit should I choose?
あーこれもいいけど...
Oh, this one's good too, but...
いやいやこっちでも...
No, no, this way...
いやいやこの服...
No, no, this outfit...
いやこっち！
No, this one!
この衣装に決定ー！
I've decided on this outfit!
着替えますよー！
I'm changing!
行くぞー！
Here I go!
みんな聞いてねー！
Everyone, please listen!
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もうずっとずっとずっとステージにいて
Please stay on the stage forever, and ever, and ever
絶対アイドル辞めないで
作詞：指原莉乃 / 作曲：小池竜暉 / 菊池博人
Never Stop Being an Idol
Lyrics: Sashihara Rino / Music: Koike Ryuki / Kikuchi Hiroto
もし君の所 離れたなら
If I were to leave your side
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
I wonder if you'd be a little lonely
意地悪なこと考える
I think of such mean things
好きな人がいるのなら
If you have someone you like
内緒にしててね
Keep it a secret
神様は将来の指輪を
God, please hide the ring
どこかに隠してね
of the future somewhere
君の好きに合わせた髪の色
The hair color matched to your preference
私の中君だけで
Within me, there's only you
満場一致は中毒へ
Unanimous agreement leads to addiction
責任取ってね 大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you
せーの！
One, two!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an idol
優しい目も真面目顔も
From your kind eyes to your serious face
すべて知ってる私が言う
I, who know everything, say so
絶対そんなで輝いて
Definitely keep shining just like that
星のまちじゃ輝かないの
You won't shine in a city of stars
眩しい君が世界一だよ
Dazzling you are the best in the world
君の夢は何ですか
What is your dream?
教えてほしい
I want to know
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't being an idol
覚悟はしてるから
I'm prepared
星のいない空 それが当たり前で
A sky without stars, that's what's normal
暗い道に目鼻立たずに
Without a landmark on the dark road
踏み出すのも怖かった
I was afraid to step forward
そんな時やっと見えた光
Then, I finally saw a light
絶対君は歌ってて
Definitely keep singing
まだ迷い言葉あっても
Even if you still have hesitant words
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
Sparkly outfits suit you
絶対大きなステージで
Definitely on a big stage
指先までも前で感じたい
I want to feel you right in front of me, even to your fingertips
今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
I kind of like how you sang today
君の努力 私の愛
Your effort, my love
成り立つこの関係は
this relationship we've built
強くて脆いの 星の幸せを願った
Is strong and fragile, I wished for the stars' happiness
だけど でもね
But... you know...
だって君はアイドルよ
After all, you're an idol
初めて目が合った日から
Since the day our eyes first met
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
today and tomorrow are all about you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an idol
これは報われない御伽話
This is an unrewarded fairy tale
恋よりももっと好きな魔法よ
a magic I love more than love
どうか解けないままで
Please, let it remain unbroken
うわあ！ねねの新しい衣装どうだった？
Whoa! How was Nene's new outfit?
最後のゲストの曲選んじゃう？
Shall I pick the song for the last guest?
よーし、この曲に... 決定！
Alright, I'll decide on this song... Decided!
今日はおまるんがいないから、おまるんの曲をね、
Since Omarun isn't here today,
コラボで歌っていきたいと思います！
I want to sing Omarun's song in a collaboration!
どの衣装で歌おうかなー？
Which outfit should I wear to sing?
はい、みんな見たいと思うので、新衣装に決定！
Okay, I think everyone wants to see it, so I decided on the new outfit!
選ばせない！
I won't let you choose!
はい変身します、変身します！
Okay, I'm transforming, I'm transforming!
はい見て！可愛い！
Yes, look! Cute!
ご覧あれ！
Take a look!
はらはらエブリワン
Hara hara everyone
微睡むオンステージ
Slumbering on stage
来日感じ
Feeling the arrival
さあ 始めよう
Come on, let's begin
ようこそパーティーナイト
Welcome to the party night
誰かが語る
Someone is talking
連日マイオンレース
Consecutive my-own-race
どうぞご贔屓に
Please favor me
待っててショータイム
Wait for the showtime
誰かが語る
Someone is talking
どうでもいいような顔を見せてよね
Show me your "I don't care" face
エンジョイ なんて 贅沢 言いませんか
Why not say that enjoying yourself is a luxury?
今辿り着いた憧れの世界
The world of my dreams I've finally reached
ここはまるでペテン師の楽園
It's like a swindler's paradise
吐き気を飲み込む
Gulping down the nausea
全幕 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
The curtain rose on all acts with that onomatopoeia
着飾る人形はピエロに口付けを
The dressed-up doll kisses the clown
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
A grand finale today, the script is laughing
騙されてくれる あなた達と
Together with you all who let me deceive you
私今ここで何をしてる
What am I doing here right now?
耳を劈く 拍手喝采
The ear-splitting applause
ザルも踊ればヒトにもなれる
If even a monkey dances, it can become human
フォーカスされた日常 引き金を描いて
A focused daily life, drawing the trigger
演ずるように
As if performing
一回 二回 三回 嘘を重ねて
Once, twice, thrice, piling up the lies
十回 千回 億回 瞳を逸らして
Ten, a thousand, a hundred million times, averting my eyes
誰なんだっけかな 私は あれ
Wait, who was I again? Oh...
飽和した 仮面 ぶっ飛んで
The saturated mask flies off
独りと孤独なワルツでお出迎え
Welcomed with a solo, lonely waltz
脱作の中
Amidst the artifice
あどけてみせて
Try to look innocent
あたしの世界はグルグル回ってく
My world keeps spinning round and round
全幕 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
The curtain rose on all acts with that onomatopoeia
群がる人形はダリアの花束を
The swarming dolls hold bouquets of dahlias
選んでくれた服を着て踊りましょう
Let's dance wearing the clothes you chose for me
騙されてくれる あなた達と
Together with you all who let me deceive you
いいよ もう これが好きだっただけなのだ
It's fine now, I just loved this, that's all
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off the persona
悲劇は喜劇と化してなお
Even as tragedy turns into comedy
今日も普通に楽しかったよ
Today was fun in the usual way
さあ 括目してくれよ
Now, keep your eyes on me
本当の僕は僕じゃないから
Because the real me isn't me
今日も普通に楽しかったよ
Today was fun in the usual way
なぜ？
Why?
全幕 幕が閉じた そのオノマトペ
The curtain fell on all acts with that onomatopoeia
着せ替え人形と輪廻のアンコール
A dress-up doll and the encore of reincarnation
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
A grand finale today, the script is laughing
どうしようもないよな
There's nothing to be done, is there?
どこを誰でもいい 調子に乗るなよと
Anyone, anywhere, just tell me not to get ahead of myself
ただ言い聞かせてくれ
Just keep telling me that
そういや夢も散々見てたな
Come to think of it, I've had plenty of dreams
もう後戻りは叶わないと
Knowing there's no going back anymore
気づけばそこには一人で
And I find myself there all alone
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off the persona
どうせフィクションの物語
It's just a fictional story anyway
この物語はフィクションです。
This story is a work of fiction.
はーい！
Hi there!
いぇーい！ お疲れ様ー！
Yay! Good job everyone!
というわけで、おまるの「ペルソナ」を、ラミィと、ししろんと、歌いましたー！
So, we sang Polka's 'Persona' together with Lamy and Shishiron!
いぇーい！
Yay!
おまる見てるー？
Polka, are you watching?
頑張ってるよおまる！
We're doing our best, Polka!
見とるかなー？
I wonder if she's watching?
見てるのかな？ 見てはいない… 見れない… 見れないな…
Is she? She's not... she can't... she can't watch right now...
ステージ頑張ってね！
Good luck with your stage performance!
頑張れー！
Go for it!
ねねたち、やり切ったよな、ペルソナ。
We really gave it our all with Persona.
やり切ったー！
We sure did!
いや、でもその前に、この新衣装について触れなくていいのー！？
Wait, but before that, shouldn't we mention this new costume!?
いぇーい！
Yay!
いいお色でしょう？
It's a nice color, right?
緑担当をいただきます。
I'll take the green color!
あー、まあまあでも、確かにこれは否定できないんだよな。
Ah, well, you certainly can't deny that.
これはなー。
It really is...
二人にはですね、この後のメンゲンのアフターパーティーにて...
To you two, in the members-only after-party later...
撮影会、カメラマンとして参加していただきます！
I'd like you to participate in the photoshoot as cameramen!
はい！参加します！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! We'll participate! Please have us!
え、どうどう？ちょっとラミィ感ある感じじゃない？
Hey, what do you think? Doesn't it have a bit of a Lamy-vibe?
ないだろ。どこに、ある？
It doesn't. Where is it?
でも、なんかちょっと妖精っぽいっちゃ妖精っぽい。
But it is a little fairy-like, if anything.
でしょでしょ！妖精っぽいよ。
Right, right! It's fairy-like.
ちょっと背中向けて。
Turn your back for a second.
はーい。あ、どうどう？緑担当と緑担当。
Okay. Oh, how's this? The green roles.
緑担当？
Green roles?
ちょっと緑っぽくない？衣装全体的に。そう、エメラルドグリーンっぽい。
Doesn't it look a bit green? The outfit as a whole. Yeah, like emerald green.
でもなんか薄ら、なんかちょっとぽいよね。
But it does look a little bit like it, faintly.
ねー。あ、お靴も可愛いでしょ。
Yeah. Oh, the shoes are cute too, right?
あ、可愛い。足、足、足。
Oh, cute. Feet, feet, feet.
ねえね、でもそれメンゲンでやったほうがいいんじゃない？
Nene, shouldn't you do that on the members-only stream instead?
あ、確かに。見せられない、見せられない。
Ah, true. Can't show it, can't show it.
やめて、見ないで！見ないで！まだ見ないで！
Stop, don't look! Don't look! Don't look yet!
まだ見ないでください。じゃあ、雑談だ、雑談だよ。
Please don't look yet. Then, let's just chat, let's chat.
というわけで、ぼたんとラミィはですね、この後ももう少し出ていきたいと思いますので...
So, Botan and Lamy will be appearing a bit more later on...
一旦、下がっていただいて。
So for now, please head backstage.
はい、下がります。ありがとうございました。
Okay, heading back. Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました。お邪魔しました。また後で！
Thank you very much. Sorry for intruding. See you later!
また後で来るわ。はーい。
I'll come back later. Bye!
はい、というわけで、三人が来て、ボルテージもアゲアゲになったところで...
All right, so with the three of us here, and the excitement reaching a peak...
次の曲、行ってみたいと思います。どうぞ！
I'd like to move on to the next song. Here it is!
ライブも後半戦！次はどの曲にしよう？
The live is in its second half! Which song should I pick next?
うーん、この曲にしようかな？
Hmm, maybe this song?
よし！この曲に決定！
All right! Decided on this song!
あれ？あれ？始まってる？これ始まってる？
Huh? Oh? Has it started? Is this starting?
あれ、始まってるみたい。あ、どうしよう、どうしよう。間違えちゃった。
Oh, looks like it's starting. Ah, what should I do, what should I do? I made a mistake.
どの曲、どの衣装で歌おうかなー。
I wonder which song and which outfit I should sing in...
えっと、えっと、これでもいいし、これって...
Um, um, this one is fine too, but this is...
あの、すみません、これって...あ、ちょっとみんな耳塞いでて。みんな耳塞いでて。
Um, sorry, this is... oh, everyone, cover your ears. Everyone, cover your ears for a second.
スタッフさんこれって...あ、ちょっとあれですよね。チェンジな感じですよね。
Staff-san, this... oh, it's that, right? It's like a change.
あ、オッケー。え、カードが...
Ah, okay. Eh, the card is...
あ、あ、なんで？待って、変わらないで。待って待って待って。まだ、まだ、まだ。
Ah, ah, why? Wait, don't change. Wait, wait, wait. Not yet, not yet, not yet.
え、曲が、曲がさ...まだ、まだ、やめてやめて。おお、危ない危ない危ない。
Wait, the song, the song is... not yet, not yet, stop it, stop it. Whoa, dangerous, dangerous, dangerous.
えっと、曲がね、ちょっと、やり直そうか。やり直そうか。
Um, the song, well, let's restart a bit. Shall we restart?
ちょっともう一回、ゲーム画面戻れ！戻れ戻れ！
Go back to the game screen one more time! Go back, go back!
次の曲、これじゃないのがいいなー。これじゃないかもなー。
For the next song, I'd prefer something else. Maybe it's not this one...
から、一回曲選択画面に戻りたいなって。戻れるかな？
So, I'd like to go back to the song selection screen for a moment. Can I go back?
戻れるかな？あれあれあれ。いや、ちょっと待って、みんな。
Can I go back? Uh oh, uh oh. No, wait a second, everyone.
あ、ちょっとやだ。見られちゃうよ。どうしよう。ねえ、二人ともどうしよう！
Ah, I don't like this. People will see me. What should I do? Hey, you two, what should I do?!
助けて二人ともー！「ねねー！」「わー！」ありがと、ありがと。
Help me, you two! "Nene!" "Waah!" Thanks, thanks.
いいよ、繋いどくよ！
It's okay, we'll keep things going!
ありがとう！あ、やばい、見られてる、見られてる。ちょっと、まだなんだけど。
Thank you! Ah, oh no, I'm being seen, I'm being seen. Wait, it's not time yet.
ちょっとみんな、ねね、ねね間違えちゃった。
Wait everyone, Nene, Nene made a mistake.
俺たちが、俺たちがコメントを読む！
We'll, we'll read the comments!
ちょっとねね落ち着こう。水飲め、水飲め。タイミング、今、飲め。
Wait, Nene, let's calm down. Drink some water. This is the timing, drink now.
おっしゃ、コメントもみんな、大丈夫。焦るな、焦るな。
All right, everyone in the comments too, it's okay. Don't panic, don't panic.
あ、ちょっと見ないで。十字キーボタンです。ありがと、二人ともマジ助かる。
Ah, don't look. It's the D-pad button. Thanks, you two, seriously a lifesaver.
大丈夫。いいよ、何でもするよ。もう一曲やるかもしれない。
It's okay. We'll do anything. We might do another song.
万歳しといて、万歳！ブルクラならできると思います。すぐ。
Do a banzai! We can do BlueClas. Right away.
ブルクラやるか。なんか、またなんか読んで。なんか読んで。
Should we do BlueClas? Read something again. Read something.
あ、わかったわかった。えっと、みんな今から、あの、本当は...
Ah, I see, I see. Um, everyone, from now on, um, actually...
ねー！
Hey!
でもちょっと、でも間違っちゃったみたいなので、
But wait, it seems I made a bit of a mistake, so...
生きてこそ歌いまーす！
I'm going to sing "Ikite Koso"!
そのために、なんだけど、
And for that reason,
ちょっと衣装、衣装ちょっと出して、衣装。
I need to get out the outfit, the outfit.
衣装は出るかな？あ、出る出る出る出る。
Will the outfit come out? Oh, it's coming out.
ちょっとねねね、生きてこそは森の民のね、お話だからね、ムシキングは。
You see, "Ikite Koso" is a story about the forest people, like in Mushiking.
だからねねちょっと森の民になりたくて、
So Nene wanted to become one of the forest people,
はい、今！はい、今お願いします！
Okay, now! Please, do it now!
キラキラキラキラキラキラ！
Sparkle sparkle sparkle sparkle sparkle!
わー、なんだ？あー！
Wow, what is this? Ah!
ちょっと何かの変化が見えたー！
I can see some kind of change!
この衣装に決定！
I've decided on this outfit!
うーん、何だと言うんだ、何だと言うんだー！
Hmm, what could it be? What could it be!?
イエーイ！
Yay!
妖精さん衣装で、聞いてください。生きてこそ！
In my fairy outfit, please listen to "Ikite Koso"!
ママ私が生まれた日の
Mama, on the day I was born,
空はどんな色
what color was the sky?
パパ私が生まれた日の
Papa, on the day I was born,
気持ちはどうだった
how did you feel?
あれから言葉を覚えて
Since then, I've learned words,
私なりの愛も甘え方も
my own way of loving and seeking affection,
体に染み込んだ
has soaked into my being.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
今ここから始まる
everything begins from right here, right now.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
広がってまた繋がる
things spread out and connect once more.
ママ私を初めて抱く
Mama, when you held me for the first time,
気持ちはどうだった
how did you feel?
パパ私が生まれた日は
Papa, on the day I was born,
嬉しかった？
were you happy?
あれから奇跡を重ねて
Since then, miracles have piled up,
私なりの愛も出会いも
my own way of loving and my encounters,
育てて行きたい
are things I want to nurture.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
無限に羽ばたいていく夢
dreams flap their wings into infinity.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
その根は深く太く強く
those roots grow deep, thick, and strong.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
今ここから始まる
everything begins from right here, right now.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
広がってまた繋がる
things spread out and connect once more.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
無限に羽ばたいていく夢
dreams flap their wings into infinity.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ
Simply by living, simply by living,
その根は深く太く強く
those roots grow deep, thick, and strong.
羽ばたいて
Flap your wings
生きてこそ
Simply by living
Ikite koso
はい、というわけで、立て直し完了。
Alright, so the recovery is complete.
というわけで、『生きてこそ』でした。
That was "Ikite koso"!
そして見てください、これ。妖精バージョンと言います！
And look at this! It's called the Fairy Version!
ちょっとね、あんまり詳しい変化は、や、教えられないかもなんだけど、
I might not be able to point out every little detail, but...
まず足が素足になっちゃいました。
First of all, I'm barefoot now.
森の妖精っぽいでしょ？
Doesn't it make me look like a forest fairy?
そして、ズボンだったのがスカートに変わっちゃいました。
Also, my pants have changed into a skirt.
そして、バサッ、羽が生えました！イエーイ！
And... flap! I've grown wings! Yay!
詳しくはメン限でもまたじっくり見てください。
Please take a closer look during the members-only stream.
さあ、ちょっとね、遅れ取っちゃったので、どんどん行きたいと思います。
Now, since we're a bit behind, I want to keep moving.
次の曲行ってみよう！
Let's go to the next song!
ライブも後半戦、次はどの曲にしよう？
The live is in its second half. What song should be next?
うーん、この曲にしようかな？
Hmm, should I go with this one?
よし、この曲に決定！
Alright, I've decided on this song!
この衣装はどの衣装で遊ぼうかな？
Which outfit should I wear for this song?
というわけで、ここからは視聴者参加型、
So, from here on out, we'll have audience participation!
ねねの次『未来形Answer』を歌う服装はみんなにアンケートで決めていただきたいと思います！
I'd like everyone to decide which outfit I'll wear to sing "Miraikei Answer" via a poll!
コメントでアンケート取るので参加してください。
I'll be taking a poll in the comments, so please join in.
選択肢は、さっきの桃鈴ねねの、えー新衣装カジュアル衣装、羽生えてない方ですね。
The options are the new casual outfit for Momosuzu Nene that I just showed—the one without wings.
そして、ねねの今着てるお洋服、妖精バージョンのねね。
And the outfit I'm wearing right now, Fairy Version Nene.
そして、この配信で初お披露目のカラーライズ衣装。
And finally, the "Colorize" outfit, which is making its debut in this stream.
次の曲はね、うんふわっと可愛い、力強めの曲ですね。
The next song is a soft, cute, yet powerful one.
この曲に合ったお洋服をみんなで選んでください。
Please choose an outfit that fits the song.
それではアンケートスタート！
And with that, let the poll begin!
待ちます待ちます。お水も飲みます。
I'll wait, I'll wait. I'm going to drink some water.
じゃー。汗、足、汗、汗で、足ドバドバになっちゃったみんな。
*Gulp*. Everyone, my feet are totally drenched in sweat.
どれにしてくれるのかな、みんな。
Which one will you choose, everyone?
どれどれどれどれ、今のところは、おお、えっ、どうしようどうしよう、みんな何着せてくれるの？
Let's see, let's see... Oh! What should I do? What are you going to make me wear?
いい勝負。いい勝負だみんな。
It's a close race. It's really close, everyone.
どうなっちゃうのかな？何かな？
What's going to happen? Which one will it be?
どれどれにしてくれるの、みんな。あ、迷う？
Which one will you choose for me? Oh, are you undecided?
カラーライズも見たい。え、だよねだよね。
You want to see "Colorize" too. Yeah, right, right!
後からね、あの、この衣装はね、メン限でいっぱい見れちゃうからね。
You'll be able to see plenty of this outfit during the members-only stream later.
カラーライズもいいな。でもせっかくなら新衣装ゆっくり見たくもあるでしょう。
"Colorize" is nice too. But since we're here, you probably want a good look at the new outfit, right?
どれがいいかな？
Which one should it be?
もう少し、まだかな？あと何分くらい？
A little longer... not yet? How many more minutes?
あと30秒で、あの、締め切りたいと思いますので、皆さん、選んでねー。
I'll be closing the poll in about 30 seconds, so please make your choice.
今参加してきてくれた人、次のねねが歌う服を今みんなにアンケートで決めてもらっております。
For those who just joined, everyone is currently deciding on the outfit I'll wear for the next song.
もうすぐで投票終わっちゃうので、まだ押してない人はポチー！
The voting is almost over, so if you haven't voted yet, click it now!
どっちかな？どれかな？どっちかな？どれかな？
Which one? Which one? Which one will it be?
終了！
Time's up!
結果は、お、すごい、いい勝負なんですけど、
The results are... Oh, wow, it's really close, but...
カラーライズ衣装で決定ー！
The "Colorize" outfit is the winner!
それじゃあ、歌っていきましょう！未来形Answer！
Alright then, let's sing! "Miraikei Answer"!
追いつけない 追いつきたいのに
I can't catch up, even though I want to
突然物語 日々なんさ
Life is a sudden story every day
分からないよアンサー
I don't know the answer
未来形Answer
Miraikei Answer
お菓子みたいに隙間
Gaps just like sweets
レシピ通りにいけばいいのに
If only they'd follow the recipe
メレンゲみたいに距離も
Just like a meringue, if only distance
時間次第で変わればいいのに
Could change depending on time
冷静と情熱とその中間になった
Between calmness and passion, I've become the middle ground
一生でも繋げないままだな　やだよ
We can't connect even in a lifetime, I hate it
追いつけない
I can't catch up
追いつきたいのに
Even though I want to catch up
突然物語　ギブミーアンサー
A sudden story, give me an answer
不器用で
So clumsy
ぎこちないほど
And so awkward
愛しく始まるの　ギブミーアンサー
It begins so dearly, give me an answer
未来形Answer
Future-tense Answer
アイシングで描く
Drawing with icing
未来図に降る
Falling on the map of the future
アラザンの雨
A rain of silver dragees
オレンジピール苦い
Orange peel is bitter
ビタースウィートで奥が深いな
It's bittersweet and profound
冗談じゃない体張ってない？
No joke, aren't you risking yourself?
ちゃんと聞きたいの
I want to hear it properly
見当違いやめて私を見て
Stop being so off the mark and look at me
早く
Quickly
何でもない
It's nothing
何もないけど
There's nothing, but
明日は晴れるかな　ギブミーアンサー
I wonder if it'll be sunny tomorrow, give me an answer
優しいね
You're kind
それで苦しいの
And that's why it's painful
次いつ会えるかな　ギブミーアンサー
I wonder when we'll meet again, give me an answer
未完成Answer
Incomplete Answer
溜息の飛ぶ夜
A night of flying sighs
ありがとうと言いたかった
I wanted to say thank you
あの日から　熱がずっと下がらないの
Since that day, my fever hasn't gone down
追いつけない
I can't catch up
追いつきたいのに
Even though I want to catch up
私の物語　ギブミーアンサー
My story, give me an answer
不器用で
So clumsy
ぎこちないほど
And so awkward
愛しく始まるの　ギブミーアンサー
It begins so dearly, give me an answer
未来形Answer
Future-tense Answer
教えないよAnswer
I won't tell you the Answer
分かりたいよAnswer
I want to understand the Answer
はい！というわけで、未来形Answerをお聞きいただきました！
Yes! And that was "Miraikei Answer"!
みんな選んでくれてありがとねー！
Thank you everyone for choosing it!
オレンジのアクセントね、めっちゃこの衣装に映えてて、
The orange accents really pop on this outfit,
可愛いと思っております！イェーイ！
and I think it's so cute! Yay!
そして今からなんですけれども、皆さんにお知らせがあります！
And now, I have an announcement for everyone!
というわけで、ししらみもおいで〜！
So, Shishi-Lami, come on out!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
ちょ、さっきマジでありがと！
Wait, thanks so much for earlier!
ブルクラならいつでもできるぞ！
We can do BLUE CLAPPER anytime!
やるか今から？
Should we do it now?
マジであちぃ...
It's really hot...
ブルクラだけ用意しとこうぜ今から
Let's just get ready for BLUE CLAPPER now.
ちょっと、椅子持ってきて！
Wait, bring a chair!
椅子用意しといてくれ！
Have a chair ready!
大丈夫、いつでも行けるぞ！
It's okay, we can go anytime!
めっちゃびっくりしちゃった。なん、なんですか！？
I was so surprised. Wha... what is it!?
おーしーらーせ！
An-nounce-ment!
おしらせ！
Announcement!
はい！おしらせね、はい！
Yes! The announcement, right!
桃鈴ねね誕生日記念グッズが出ます！イェーイ！
Momosuzu Nene Birthday Commemoration Goods are coming out! Yay!
イェーイ！どんなの？どんなの？
Yay! What kind? What kind?
全体はこちら！どん！
Here's the full lineup! Bam!
桃鈴ねね誕生日記念2025！
Momosuzu Nene Birthday Celebration 2025!
可愛い！
Cute!
新衣装のなんとグッズが初めて出ます！
Goods featuring the new outfit are coming out for the first time!
おー、いいね！
Oh, nice!
一つずつ見ていきましょう。1つ目はこちら！どん！
Let's look at them one by one. First is this! Bam!
キャンバスアート
Canvas Art
あ、ちょっと目に汗が...
Ah, wait, sweat in my eye...
大丈夫？目薬？
Are you okay? Eye drops?
よしよし。
There, there.
ちょっとさ、ちょっとキャンバスアート紹介してくれ！
Wait, can you guys introduce the canvas art for a bit!?
はい、はい。はい、こちらのキャンバスアートはですね、ねねちの...
Yes, yes. Well, this canvas art is Nenechi's...
獅白ぼたん：まずはこちら、新3D衣装のですね...
Shishiro Botan: First, we have this one from the new 3D outfit...
獅白ぼたん：キャンバスアート。可愛い森の妖精チックな。
Shishiro Botan: The canvas art. It has a cute forest fairy-like feel.
雪花ラミィ：キャンバスアート、待って可愛いからね！
Yukihana Lamy: Wait, the canvas art is so cute!
雪花ラミィ：今回の衣装めっちゃ映えてる。
Yukihana Lamy: It really shows off this new outfit.
桃鈴ねね：なんかね、聞いた話によると、私以外みんな出してるらしいのよ。
Momosuzu Nene: You know, from what I heard, everyone but me is releasing one.
雪花ラミィ：え、待って、ねぽらぼで？
Yukihana Lamy: Wait, in NePolabo?
獅白ぼたん：ねぽらぼで？
Shishiro Botan: In NePolabo?
獅白ぼたん：ねぽらぼね。
Shishiro Botan: In NePolabo, right.
雪花ラミィ：ねぽらぼね。
Yukihana Lamy: In NePolabo, right.
桃鈴ねね：ねぽらぼで、ねね以外全員キャンバスアート出してると思って。
Momosuzu Nene: I thought everyone in NePolabo except Nene was releasing canvas art.
雪花ラミィ：いや、私たち、関係なかったここ。
Yukihana Lamy: No, we weren't involved in that part.
獅白ぼたん：ししろんもまだ出してなかったから。
Shishiro Botan: Shishiron hadn't released one either.
桃鈴ねね：そうね。はい、そして次！
Momosuzu Nene: Right. Okay, and next!
桃鈴ねね：ねっ子証明書！
Momosuzu Nene: The Nekko Certificate!
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：わあー！いいですよ、これは！
Botan/Lamy: Whoa! This is nice!
桃鈴ねね：これは、昔ねねが「ねねプロの証明書」っていうのを作った時に...
Momosuzu Nene: This is... back when I made the 'NenePro Certificate'...
桃鈴ねね：...まだその時ねねのねっ子じゃなかったみんなが、「僕も欲しい、僕も欲しい」ってしてくれたので...
Momosuzu Nene: ...everyone who wasn't a Nekko yet said, 'I want one too, I want one too'...
桃鈴ねね：...2回目で！
Momosuzu Nene: ...so this is the second time!
桃鈴ねね：ねぽらぼの... あ、じゃない、ねぽらぼじゃない、巻き込んじゃった。
Momosuzu Nene: The NePolabo... wait, not NePolabo. I got mixed up.
雪花ラミィ：焦りすぎてる！落ち着いて！
Yukihana Lamy: You're too flustered! Calm down!
獅白ぼたん：落ち着いて、落ち着いて。大丈夫だよ。
Shishiro Botan: Calm down, calm down. It's okay.
桃鈴ねね：ねっ子の証明書が出ます！
Momosuzu Nene: The Nekko Certificate is coming out!
桃鈴ねね：グレーになってるところがあると思うんだけど...
Momosuzu Nene: I think there's a part that's grayed out...
桃鈴ねね：...そこはみんながオリジナルのねっ子を作り上げて...
Momosuzu Nene: ...I want everyone to create their own original Nekko there...
桃鈴ねね：...ここに写真貼ったり、名前書いたり、色塗ったりして欲しいなーっていう思いを込めて。
Momosuzu Nene: ...by pasting a photo, writing their name, or coloring it in.
雪花ラミィ：でも、ねっ子の保存方法、瓶の中なんだ。
Yukihana Lamy: Wait, the way to preserve the Nekko is in a jar!
獅白ぼたん：液体に浸かってる！
Shishiro Botan: It's submerged in liquid!
桃鈴ねね：あ、やってあれば一生元気にいられる。
Momosuzu Nene: Ah, if you do that, it'll stay healthy forever.
獅白ぼたん：まあ確かにな、空気入ってないからね。ホルマリン漬け。
Shishiro Botan: True, no air gets in. Like a formalin specimen.
桃鈴ねね：そう。そしてシリアルナンバーが入ってます。
Momosuzu Nene: Right. And it has a serial number.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：おお、いいですね！可愛い可愛い。
Botan/Lamy: Oh, nice! So cute.
桃鈴ねね：そして裏面は、りいちゅ先生が描いてくれたイラストに、ねねからのメッセージが付いてきます。
Momosuzu Nene: And on the back is an illustration by Riichu-sensei with a message from me.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：いいですねー！
Botan/Lamy: That's great!
桃鈴ねね：そして次！ねっ子タンブラー！
Momosuzu Nene: And next! The Nekko Tumbler!
桃鈴ねね：ちょっと大人っぽい感じのデザイン。
Momosuzu Nene: It has a slightly mature design.
雪花ラミィ/獅白ぼたん：余白多めだったんだね。今回はだいぶ余白...
Lamy/Botan: There's a lot of negative space. Quite a bit of negative space this time...
桃鈴ねね：今回は余白を活かした感じにして。
Momosuzu Nene: I wanted to make it feel like it makes use of the negative space.
桃鈴ねね：みんながコンビニでよく飲んでるあのコーヒーのカップ...
Momosuzu Nene: You know that coffee cup you often drink from the convenience store...
桃鈴ねね：...あれがスポッとそのまま入るサイズ。
Momosuzu Nene: ...it's the size where that fits right in.
桃鈴ねね：なのでおしゃれ隠れねっ子グッズとして使ってください。
Momosuzu Nene: So please use it as some stylish, subtle Nekko goods.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：可愛い！おしゃれ！めっちゃ欲しいわ。
Botan/Lamy: So cute! Stylish! I really want one.
桃鈴ねね：そして次！ねっ子ぬいぐるみカレンダー！
Momosuzu Nene: And next! The Nekko Plushie Calendar!
桃鈴ねね：これはね、マジいつになっても使えるカレンダーですね。
Momosuzu Nene: This is a calendar you can seriously use forever.
桃鈴ねね：そして真ん中の、鏡みたいになってるところが...
Momosuzu Nene: And the part in the middle that looks like a mirror...
桃鈴ねね：...チェキ風のブロマイド。あれがピッタリ中に入るようになっております。
Momosuzu Nene: ...is where a Polaroid-style bromide card fits perfectly inside.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：いい、便利！
Botan/Lamy: Nice, that's convenient!
桃鈴ねね：お気に入りのホロメンとか、ねねのブロマイドのカードを入れてください。
Momosuzu Nene: Please put in your favorite Holo members or Nene's bromide cards.
桃鈴ねね：そして上のねっ子の部分なんだけど、これなんと取り外しができます！
Momosuzu Nene: And as for the Nekko part on top, you can actually remove it!
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：おおー、ぬいぐるみの部分？
Botan/Lamy: Oh, the plushie part?
桃鈴ねね：そう、ねっ子のぬいぐるみとして使えるので、みんな何処かにキーホルダーとして飾ったりとか、そういうこともできちゃいます。
Momosuzu Nene: Right, it works as a Nekko plushie, so you can display it as a keychain or something like that.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：いいですね、可愛い！
Botan/Lamy: That's nice, so cute!
桃鈴ねね：スポッと取れてね、磁石になってるんだったかな。
Momosuzu Nene: It pops right off, and I think it's magnetic.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：あ、へえ！ピタってどっかにくっつけることができる。冷蔵庫ね！
Botan/Lamy: Oh, really! So you can stick it anywhere. Like the fridge!
桃鈴ねね：そうそう、だから色んなところにねっ子と一緒にねねを旅に連れてって下さい。
Momosuzu Nene: Exactly, so please take Nene and the Nekko on a trip with you.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：可愛い！
Botan/Lamy: Cute!
桃鈴ねね：そしてドン！ボイス！おまけにねねのボイスも出ます！
Momosuzu Nene: And boom! Voice! As a bonus, Nene's voice pack is coming out too!
雪花ラミィ：どんなボイスなんだい？
Yukihana Lamy: What kind of voice is it?
桃鈴ねね：「きみと二人で誕生日パーティー！」
Momosuzu Nene: 'A Birthday Party with Just the Two of Us!'
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：おおー！二人で祝うんですね。
Botan/Lamy: Whoa! So we're celebrating with just the two of us.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：俺たちを差し置いて！ねぽらぼはどうした！？
Botan/Lamy: Leaving us behind! What about NePolabo?!
雪花ラミィ：こんな汗ビチャビチャで紹介するもんじゃないけど。
Yukihana Lamy: Not that you should introduce it while all sweaty like this.
桃鈴ねね：ねねとねっ子二人きりのね、ラブラブイチャイチャ誕生日ボイスが出ます！
Momosuzu Nene: A lovey-dovey birthday voice pack with just Nene and Nekko is coming out!
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：まあ誕生日だしな、しょうがねえ。
Botan/Lamy: Well, it is her birthday, so it can't be helped.
桃鈴ねね：そしてフルセットがこちら！キャンバスアート、ねっ子証明書、タンブラー、カレンダー、ボイス、そしてチェキ風ブロマイドカード！
Momosuzu Nene: And here's the full set! Canvas art, certificate, tumbler, calendar, voice pack, and the Polaroid-style card!
桃鈴ねね：ピッタリ入ります、ねのカレンダーの中に、今回のね。
Momosuzu Nene: It fits perfectly inside that calendar we just showed.
桃鈴ねね：そして今回は、ちょっと申し訳ないのですが...
Momosuzu Nene: And this time, I'm very sorry, but...
桃鈴ねね：...数量限定バージョンがあります！
Momosuzu Nene: ...there's a limited quantity version!
桃鈴ねね：数量限定バージョン買っていただくと、ねねの直筆サインプラス、メッセージ入りのブロマイド風チェキカードが来ます。
Momosuzu Nene: If you buy the limited edition, it comes with a handwritten signature and a message on the card.
桃鈴ねね：そしてフルセットには、箔押しサイン複製サイン付きのものが付きます。
Momosuzu Nene: And the regular full set comes with a foil-stamped/replicated signature.
桃鈴ねね：そしてフルセットをご購入してくれた皆さんには...
Momosuzu Nene: And for everyone who buys the full set...
桃鈴ねね：...こちら！ねねの台本なしフリートークボイス！
Momosuzu Nene: ...this! Nene's unscripted free talk voice!
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：なんだそりゃー！聞いたことない！台本なし！？
Botan/Lamy: What's that?! I've never heard of that! Unscripted?!
桃鈴ねね：ねねが練習とか大詰めになってる時に、みんなへのね、頑張りたいっていう思いを込めたボイスをここにギュッと収めました。
Momosuzu Nene: I packed in a voice recording of my feelings about wanting to work hard, made during the height of practice.
獅白ぼたん/雪花ラミィ：なるほど、じゃあ本音のボイスってこと？ねねの本音ボイス。
Botan/Lamy: I see, so it's a recording of your true feelings? Nene's true feelings voice.
はいはい。
Yes, yes.
そして最近話題のこちらです！
And here is the latest topic!
うわー！あー出た！
Wow! Oh, it's out!
ホルカだ！ホルカが付いてきます。
It's Holo-card! It comes with a Holo-card.
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲーム、ねねのお誕生日バージョンが、えー、フルセット1つご購入につき1枚付いてきます。
A Nene birthday version of the Hololive Official Card Game will come with every full set purchase.
これめっちゃ可愛い！
This is so cute!
可愛いですよね。
It is cute, isn't it?
なんかちょっとエモい雰囲気もあって。
It has a bit of an "emotional" atmosphere too.
いいなって思います。
I think it's nice.
そして今回なんですけれども、ちょっといろいろトラブルがありましたのでお詫びで、カートオープンがですね、21時15分になっております。
And for this time, as an apology for some troubles we had, the cart opening will be at 21:15.
おー！まだ、もうちょっと時間がある。
Oh! So there's still a bit of time.
もうちょい時間。
A little more time.
だからね、ちょっと最後まで放送見て、えー、そのあと、あの、よければチェックしていただければと思います。ぜひよろしくお願いします。
So please watch the stream until the end, and then check it out afterwards if you'd like. Thank you.
お願いしまーす！
Please!
Thank you!
今ね、コメントにも貼って固定してもらうので、よかったらそちらからチェックしてください。21時15分！
It'll be pinned in the comments now, so check it from there. 21:15!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、ねね最後の曲がありますので…
Alright, so Nene has one last song...
あ、そうだ、ブラグラもやる…（笑）ブラグラもやるわ。ありがと。一旦ちょっとメン限にブラグラやるからじゃあ。
Oh, wait, I have to do the "Blagra" too... (laughs) Let's do it. Thanks. I'll do it in the member-only stream later.
ブラグラもやろうぜ。ブリブリブリブリ…
Let's do the "Blagra" too. Buri buri buri buri...
Let's do the "Blagra"! Buri buri buri buri...
はいありがとー。失礼しました。ありがとー。またねー！
Okay, thank you! Excuse us. Thanks, see you later!
二人にはこの後のメン限放送にも出てもらいます。ありがとう！
These two will also appear in the member-only stream afterwards. Thank you!
というわけで、最後の曲行ってみましょうか！ドン！
Well then, let's go for the last song! Boom!
次は… おれ？
Next is... me?
おれ、この曲はなんだろう？
Wait, what is this song?
うわあ、もしかしてこの曲は！
Whoa, could it be this song!?
よーし、この曲行ってみちゃおう！
Alright, let's go with this song!
みんな楽しみにしててねー！
Everyone, look forward to it!
最後の、最後の曲はですね、Love受信、ビクン発信で行きたいと思います！
The last... the last song is "Love Jushin, Pikun Hasshin"!
イエーイ！こちら、ねねのお誕生日当日に出た新曲になります。MVもね、もう公開されているので、よければチェックお願いします。
Yay! This is the new song released on Nene's birthday. The MV is out too, so please check it out.
そして最後、まだね、あのさっきアンケートで選ばれなかった新衣装たちがありますので、そちらにお着替えして、最後の曲を歌っていきたいと思います。
And finally, I'll change into the outfits that weren't selected in the survey earlier and sing the last song!
どの衣装にしようかな？どっちにしようかな？
Which outfit should I pick? This one or that one?
妖精衣装で、決定！
The Fairy outfit! Decision!
うーん、時間間に合いまじっ！はっ！
Hmm, I made it in time!! Ha!
それでは聞いてください。Love受信、ビクン発信！
Now, please listen. "Love Jushin, Pikun Hasshin"!
（すき！すき！すき！にさせてみせるから）
(I'll make you fall in love, love, love with me)
こっちを向いてバカ
Look this way, you dummy
（ワクワクいっぱいの日にしてあげるから）
(Because I'll make this day full of excitement)
ねねビームで　ばきゅーん！
Nene Beam, bam!
画面前でおめかし準備
Getting all dressed up in front of the screen
今日は何にする？アイディア募集
What should I do today? Looking for ideas
そーだ！エゴサでこっそり君に
I know! I'll ego-search you secretly...
聞いてみちゃおっかな？教えてくれる？
...and ask you! Will you tell me?
「ねねちだけが、一生推しだよ！」
"Nenechi is my only one-and-only for life!"
嬉しくってハピネス
I'm so happy, it's bliss
でも、待って…
But wait...
5時間前の「最推し揺るいじゃうんゴｗ」
5 hours ago: "My favorite might change, lol"
ふざけんなよ　早く消せよ
Don't mess with me! Delete it now!
へっ☆口悪いよね
Hehe, I have a foul mouth, don't I?
秘密を持ったアイドル
An idol with secrets
信じてるこれからも　君との未来　進もう〜っ！！
I believe in our future, let's keep moving forward!!
来てくれたの　励みになるよ
You coming here encourages me
一生懸命　愛伝えるねっ
I'll do my best to convey my love
「ねねち推しです！」ありがとだけど
"I'm a Nenechi fan!" Thanks, but...
それ別の子の推しマークじゃね？
Isn't that another girl's fan mark?
DD歓迎？そんなわけない！！
DD welcome? No way!!
おいコラ浮気すんな！！！！！
Hey! Don't you dare cheat on me!!!!!
響く声が　世界中届くように
So that my echoing voice reaches the whole world
羽ばたきたい
I want to spread my wings
もっともっともっと
More, more, and more
えへっ　本当は根暗
Hehe, I'm actually a shut-in
でもめげずに　アイドル
But I won't give up on being an idol
その笑顔　限りなく　見てみたいから
Because I want to see that smile of yours forever
思いを込めて　こんねね～！あいうらびゅ～♡
With all my heart, Konnene~! I love you~♡
「最推しかわいい///」　えへっ　サンキュー♡
"My favorite is so cute///" Hehe, thank you♡
他の子にも言ってた　マジで処刑
If you've been saying that to other girls, it's seriously execution for you
ねねねねねねね...ねねだけだよねねね...？
Nene-nene-nene-nene-nene... It's only Nene, right...?
金髪ってだけで　陽キャだと思うなよ
Don't think I'm an extrovert just because I have blonde hair
引きこもるぞ　泣いて　マジかよ
I'll shut myself in and cry, for real
えへっ☆　卑屈者の
Hehe☆ An underdog's...
光まとった　アイドル
...light-clad idol
信じてるこれからも　君といること
I believe that from now on, I'll be with you
せーの！「はい」っ！！あーーーーーー☆
One, two! "Yes"!! Ahhhhhhh☆
好き好き好きにさせてみせるから
Because I'll make you like, like, like me
こっちを向いててよ！
Keep looking this way!
ワクワクいっぱいの日にしてくから
Because I'll make it a day full of excitement
ねねビームで　バキュン！
Nene Beam, bang!
バキュン！この後21時15分、カードオープンそしてミニゲームもよろしくね！
Bang! After this at 21:15, card opening and mini-games too, so please look forward to it!
ハッピー・ギラパ！ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！
Happy Gira-pa! Welcome to Nenechi's Gira Gira Fan Meeting!
今回は、ゲストのみんなと一緒にギラギラしていきたいと思います。それじゃあ、いくよ！
This time, I'd like to get flashy with all the guests. Well then, here we go!
アミーゴ！カバジェロ！ビバ！ギラパ！
Amigo! Caballero! Viva! Gira-pa!
カブクワ　ギラギラ　最後だ　カブクワ
Kabu-kuwa, flashy, it's the end, kabu-kuwa
ハイパ ハイパ ラブラブ ハイパ
Hyper hyper love love hyper
強くって カッコイイ
Strong and cool
キラキラ ファンタスティックな 飛び出すラブ
Sparkling fantastic popping love
宝物だね
It's a treasure
イェーイ！ ハイパ ハイパ！
Yay! Hyper hyper!
カブクワは！
Beetles and stags!
キラキラ最高な夏！
Sparkling best summer!
カブクワは！
Beetles and stags!
オレ！ カブクワ イェーイ！
Ole! Beetles and stags yay!
カブクワは！
Beetles and stags!
くりくりおめめのラブ！
Round-eyed love!
カブクワは！
Beetles and stags!
ソレ！ カブクワ イェーイ！
Sore! Beetles and stags yay!
カブクワは！ヘイ！
Beetles and stags! Hey!
ボンジュール チュッ チュッ
Bonjour, chu chu
ハイパ ハイパ ハイパパ
Hyper hyper hyper-pa
ありがとー！
Thank you!